

Springfield, Massachusetts

【 (413) 472-9082 | ■ julioapaton@gmail.com

Summary.

C++ Senior Software Engineer with 8+ years experience, has led teams to deliver critical applications in international defense programs. Motivated to continue to learn and grow as a professional and to help other team members to achieve their full potential. A Spaniard recently moved to the United States looking forward to making his first contribution.

Work Experience_

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)

Valdepeñas, Spain

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Apr. 2021 - Present

- · Mentoring new members of the team.
- Remote communication with the client for requirement specification and support.
- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link solution software.
- In-depth use of modern C++, STL, Boost, TCP/IP communications and multi-threading.

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Optronic Systems)

Valdepeñas, Spain Jan. 2020 - Mar. 21

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Use of bug finding tools such as AddressSanitizer and Valgrind. • Embedded software design and development in C/C++.
- Remote and on-site support to client.
- · CI of SW components.
- Technologies used include C++14, Xilinx SDK, Yocto Project and Jenkins.

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)

Valdepeñas, Spain

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan 2018 - Dec 2019

- Plan, organize and monitor tasks of the software development team.
- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link solution software.
- · Integration of communications systems such as network controller, modem, radio, GPS, NTP server, radar and cryptographic device.
- · On-site system deployment, testing, support and training for Bangladesh navy on ships, ground stations and aircrafts.
- In-depth use of C++, STL, Boost, TCP/IP communications and multi-threading.

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)

Valdepeñas, Spain

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jun. 2014 - Dec. 2017

- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link Systems including Link11, Link16, Link22, JREAP and SIMPLE protocols.
- Port a VxWorks Tactical Data Link processor application to Linux.
- Technologies used include C++11 and Qt.

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)

Valdepeñas, Spain Sep. 2012 - May. 2014

RESEARCH ASSISTANT · Design and develop computer vision applications for desktop, Android and iOS platforms using OpenCV.

- [Book] OpenCV Essentials, Packt Publishing, 2014.
- [Article] A Vision-Based Localization Algorithm for an Indoor Navigation App, Eighth International Conference on Next Generation Mobile Apps, Services and Technologies (NGMAST), 2014.

Education

Expert in Video Games Development

Ciudad Real, Spain

UCLM (University of Castilla - La Mancha)

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2014

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

Ciudad Real, Spain

UCLM (UNIVERSITY OF CASTILLA - LA MANCHA)

Sep. 2011 - Jun. 2013

TUE(EINDHOVEN UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY)

Erasmus Scholarship

Sep. 2009 - Jul. 2010

Eindhoven, The Netherlands

Technical Engineering in Computer Systems

Ciudad Real, Spain

UCLM(UNIVERSITY OF CASTILLA - LA MANCHA)

Sep. 2007 - Jun. 2011